Captain Boycott is a drama, history film directed by Frank Launder.
Based on real events, this historical drama is set in 19th-century Ireland, when
poverty-stricken tenants dispossessed by greedy landowner Capt.
Boycott (Cecil Parker) band together to assert their rights.
Patriotic farmer Hugh Davin (Stewart Granger) leads the rebels.
Choosing nonviolent resistance, the villagers ostracize their nemesis, who squanders his
fortune to repair his ruined reputation and wagers what's left on a horse race.
Hugh Davin, played by Stewart Granger.
Anne Killain, played by Kathleen Ryan.
Capt. Charles C. Boycott, played by Cecil Parker.
Watty Connell, played by Mervyn Johns.
Father McKeogh, played by Alastair Sim.
Daniel McGinty, played by Noel Purcell.
Captain Boycott is a 1947 British historical drama film directed by Frank Launder and starring
Stewart Granger, Kathleen Ryan, Mervyn Johns, Alastair Sim and Cecil Parker.
Robert Donat makes a cameo appearance as the Irish
nationalist leader Charles Stewart Parnell.
The film explains how the word boycott appeared in the English language.
Ironically, the titular character plays a secondary role in the film, as
an anti-hero, and the hero of the film is Hugh Davin.
The tone is dark and emotional.